Biographical files (UCLA University Archives Reference Collection). 1882- UARC.0745
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Biographical Files., 1882-; Series 1.
  - Houk, Kendall N.
  - Hovannisian, Richard C.
    UCLA faculty, History Department. Professor of Armenian and Near Eastern History; Associate Director of the Near Eastern Center at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA).
  - Howard, Tyrone.
  - Howland, Benjamin.
  - Huberfeld, Felicia.
  - Hughes, Kisa.
  - Hughes, Patricia J., b. 1943 - d. 2007.
  - Hundley, Norris Jr.
  - Hutchinson, John., b. 1921.
  - Hyry, Tom.
    Director, UCLA Library Special Collections (2010 March-2014 July).
  - Iacoboni, Marco.
  - Isherwood, Christopher., b.1906 August 26 - d.
    UCLA University Extension lecture series (3 lectures), 1961 March; UCLA Regents' Lecturer, 1965 February 1 to June 10.
  - Jackson, James R., b. 1924 - d. 2011.
  - Jackson, John B. (UCLA 1927)
  - Jacobs, Michelle.
  - Jacoby, Neil H., b. 1909 - d. 1979.
  - Jacoby, Stanford M., b. 1953.
  - Jager, Eric.
  - Jairazbhoy, Nazir.
  - Jarvik, Murray., b. 1923 - d. 2008; 1 folder
    UCLA faculty, Psychiatry and Pharmacology and co-inventor of the nicotine patch.
  - Jelliffe, Eleanore Patrice.
  - Jennings, Thomas.
  - Jentsch, J. David.
  - Jessen, Raymond J., b. 1910 - d. 2003.
  - Johnson, Carroll.
  - Johnson, Eric E.
  - Johnson, Marques.
    UCLA men's basketball team member: 1974, 1975, 1976, 1977.
  - Johnson, Walter Leland.
  - Jones, Andrew.
  - Jones, Marian Anne Bunker (UCLA 1949, M.A. 1954)
    Marian Anne Bunker Jones was formerly the Getty Museum Secretary, Acting Curator, and Curator up through 1965 May 31.
  - Jones, Thomas William.
  - Jones, Thomas., b. 1944 Sep 8 - d. 2007 March 21
  - Jonsson, Diana Gordon.
  - Jonsson, Kenneth Alan.
  - Jose, Margaret.
  - Juvonen, Jaana.
  - Kabrack, H. Ronald.
  - Kaesz, Herbert David., b.1933 January 4 - d.2012; UCLA Chemistry Department (1960- )
  - Kahn, Barbara Balter (UCLA 1956).
    1995 President of the Gold Shield Alumnae of UCLA.
  - Kantola, Bennett William.
  - Karagozian, Ann Renee.
  - Karmarker, Uday S.
  - Karrenbrock, Wilbert E.
  - Karst, Kenneth L.
    UCLA Professor of Law.
  - Kasakhian, Isgouhi.
  - Katz, Madelyn., - d.2009
  - Keddie, Nikki R. (Ragozin)., b.1930-
    UCLA Professor, History; Fellow American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1994).
  - Keeler, Emmett B.
  - Kellman, Philip.
  - Kelly, Robert E.
  - Kenan, Gil. (UCLA M.F.A. 2002)
    UCLA thesis film 'Lark;' selected by Robert Zemeckis and Steven Spielberg to direct animated commercial film 'Monster House' (2006).
  - Kennedy, George C., b.1920 - d.1980 March 18
    UCLA faculty Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics (IGPP).
  - Kennel, Charles F.
    UCLA Professor of Physics.
  - Kerckhoff, Louise E., d.1946
  - Kerckhoff, William George., b.1856 March 30 - d.1929 February 22
  - Kernan, Lisa D.
  - Kerr, Clark., b.1911 - d.2003
    Includes President of the University of California inauguration program (1958 September 26).
  - Kessler, Jascha Frederick., b.1929 Nov. 27 -
    UCLA Professor of English.
  - Key, Valdimer O., Jr.
    UCLA Political Science faculty, 1933-1935.
  - Kingsley, Joseph H.
  - Kinnory, David S.
  - Kiraly, Karch.
    UCLA men's volleyball team. NCAA All-Tournament Team: 1981, 1982.
  - Kirk, Stuart A.
  - Kissler, Gerald R.
    Vice Provost, College of Letters and Science.
  - Knapp, Betsy Wood.
  - Knopoff, Leon., b.1925 - d.2011 January 20
    UCLA faculty in Geophysics and Physics; Research Musicologist in Ethnomusicology; UCLA Faculty Research Lecturer, 1972.
  - Koropeckyj, Roman.
  - Koyama, Janice.
    Assistant/Associate University Librarian for Public Services (c.1991-2002); interim University Librarian (2002-August 2003).
  - Krachmalnick, Samuel J.
  - Kraus, Jess F.
  - Krauthammer, Marcel.
  - Krell, Heather V.
  - Kremenliev, Boris A., b. 1911 May 23 - d. 1988 Apr 25
    UCLA Faculty in Music.
  - Kunene, Mazisi (Daniel P.).
    UCLA Faculty, African Languages.
  - La Kretz, Morton.
  - Ladefoged, Peter., b.1925 September 17 - d.2006 January 26
    UCLA Emeritus Professor of Linguistics. (1962-
  - Ladner, Gerhart B.
    UCLA Professor of History.
  - Laietsky [Lasky], Benjamin., b.1884 November 16 - d.1955
    First director of the uniformed UCLA Marching Band (hired c.1928). Also known as Benjamin Lasky.
  - Lake, James.
  - Lal, Deepak Kumar.
  - Lamson, Baldwin G.
    Director of Hospitals and Clinics, Associate Dean of the School of Medicine.
  - Lao, Kan.
  - Larkin, James.
  - Lascelles, June.
  - Lasky, Benjamin. SEE: Laietsky, Benjamin.
  - Latham, Eric.
  - Lavine, Adrienne.
  - Leamer, Edward E.
  - LeBel, Alice Aileen Hall.
  - Lefkowitz, David.
  - Lehner, George.
  - Lenart, Yvonne., b.1915 - d.2010
  - Lengyel, Judith.
  - Leslie, Ruth Annette (UCLA 1932)
    Scope and Content
    Includes Ruth A. Leslie's scrapbook (photographic prints, clippings, correspondence) of the April 1932 Pi Kappa Delta National Oratorial Contest at the University of Tulsa, Oklahoma.
  - Leuchter, Andrew.
  - Levine, Gene Norman.
  - Lew, Jeffrey K.
    UCLA Professor of Atmospheric Science.
  - Lew, Rod.
  - Lewin, David.
  - Lewin, Klaus.
  - Lewis, Benjamin G.
    SEE ALSO: Trope Lewis, Rosalee Diane (UCLA 1942).
  - Lewis, Loren.
  - Liau, Linda.
  - Libby, Willard Frank.
  - Lichtheim, Miriam., b.1914 - d.2004
  - Lichtman, David.
  - Liemert, Walter H.
    Game announcer for UCLA football.
  - Lievrouw, Leah A.
  - Lifka, Thomas.
  - Light, Ivan.
  - Limon, Jose Arcadio (Attended UCLA 1927 Spring).
    Jose Limon was the founder of Jose Limon and Dance Company.
  - Lindemann, Jens.
  - Linsman, Joseph Francis.
  - Liou, K.N.
  - Lippman, Steven A., b. 1943.
  - Liu, Jia-Ming.
  - Livingston, Monte E. (UCLA 1935)., d.1998
  - Livingston, Roseline Keen (UCLA 1937)., b.1915 September 24 - d.2011 September 15
  - Locks, Matthew Owen., d.2008
  - Loeb, Sidney.
  - Loeblich-Tappaw, Helen Nina., b.1917 - d.2004
  - Lofstedt, Bengt Torkel Magnus., b.1931 - d.2004
  - Lokman, Lawrence H.
  - Long, Philomene.
  - Longman, Lester Duncan., b.1905 - d.1987 January 27
    UCLA Professor of Art; helped found the College of Fine Arts in 1960.
  - Longshore, Douglas Yale.
  - Lopez-Rodriguez, Faustino
  - Loukaitou-Sideris, Anastasia.
  - Lubetzky, Seymour., b.1898 April 28 - d.2003
    UCLA Professor, School of Library Service; UC Regents Honorary Doctor of Laws (1969).
  - Luck, Jeff.
  - Lui, Tsun Yuen., b.1931 - d.2008
  - Lyday, Dennis.
  - Lyder, Courtney.
  - Lysy, Antonio.
  - MacDonald, Glen.
  - MacFadyen, David.
  - Macías, Reynaldo.
  - Maderas, Nicole Monastersky.
  - Magoun, Horace Winchell., b.1907 - d.1991 Mar. 6
    UCLA Professor of Anatomy; 1950 - founding chair of UCLA Anatomy; founded the UCLA Brain Research Institute.
  - Mahler, Anna.
    Sculptor; appointed UCLA Lecturer in Art 1951 September; daughter of Gustav Mahler (composer and conductor) and Anna Mahler-Werfel.
  - Maier, Guy., b.1892 - d.1956
    UCLA Lecturer in Music, Department of Music. (1947/1948 General Catalog).
  - Makdisi, Saree.
  - Mal, Ajit K.
  - Malcolm X.
    Includes surveillance file [produced by Federal Bureau of Investigation?] of Malcolm X's activities.
    Formerly known as Malcolm K. Little. 1962 November 28 - Malcolm X visited UCLA to give lecture in Moore Hall on the Nation of Islam (NOI) [source: surveillance file, part 2, pg. 25]
  - Mamer, John W.
  - Mamoulian, Rouben.
  - Mancini, Henry.
  - Manczarek, Raymond Daniel (UCLA MA 1966).
    Member of The Doors (rock band).
  - Mangione, Carol.
  - Manson, Joseph.
  - Marquardt, Donald.
  - Marti, Werner H. (UCLA 1943, Ph.D. 1953).
    Member of Phi Kappa Psi; claims to be the first blind student to graduate from UCLA and the first blind student to recieve a Ph.D. from UCLA.
  - Martin, Neil.
  - Mason, Robert Hal.
  - Mason, Thomas G.
  - Masterson, Bernie Edward.
    Appointed UCLA football backfield coach as of the 1941 season.
  - Mathias Hassler, Mildred Esther., b.1906 sep 19 - d.1995 feb 16
    UCLA Emeritus Professor of Botany.
  - Matsumoto, Valerie J.
  - Maverick, Lewis Adams., b.1891
    Lewis Adams Maverick was a faculty member in the Education Department (1921-1928) and in the Economics Department (1930- ). Includes issues of "The Condition of Business" - 1933 January (v.2:1) and 1933 February (v.2:2) - published by the UCLA Class in Business Cycles, L. A. Maverick, instructor.
  - May, Genevieve S., b.1909 - d.2004
  - May, Philip R. A., b.1920-d.1986; Psychiatry Department (1956-1986); Clinical Director of the UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute (1962-1970); selected as the first UCLA Della Martin Professor of Psychiatry (1983-1986).
  - Mayne, Thom.
  - Mays, Vickie.
  - McAllister, Frances Muriel Burt (UCLA 1932)
    Includes a copy of "Journals of Frances B. McAllister, 1910-2008" with descriptions of student life at UCLA from 1930-1932.
  - McBain, Carl.
  - McBride, George McCutchen., b.1876 October 11 - d.1971 October 7
    UCLA Professor of Geography, 1922-1948.
  - McCann, Michael C.
  - McCarthy, James Howard., b.1911 June 4 - d.1975 February 11
  - McClendon, Muriel.
  - McCormick, Mona., b.1930 - d.1994 June 30
    UCLA reference librarian.
  - McCracken, James T.
  - McCullough, James Douglas., b.1905 May 17 - d.1985 January 28
    UCLA Professor of Chemistry, Emeritus.
  - McCumber, John.
  - McCutchan, Joseph W., b.1917 December 24 - d.1982 October 15
    UCLA Faculty, Chemical, Nuclear and Thermal Engineering Department.
  - McDermott, Anthony Xavior.
  - McDiarmid, Suzanne V.
  - McDonald, John.
  - McDonough, Patricia.
  - McElvy, Carl C.
    UCLA Architect, c.1946-1963; name also spelled: McElvey.
  - McGrail, Michael Lance.
  - McLaren, Peter L.
  - McLean, Ephraim R., b. 1936.
  - McManus, George Stewart., b.1886-
  - McMillan, William George, Jr., 1919 - 2002
    UCLA Professor of Chemistry; department chair, 1959-1965.
  - McNeese-Smith, Donna.
  - McWhinney, William Houston.
  - Medino, Carlo.
  - Melkanoff, Michel A.
    Includes: Proposal for University of California Manufacturing Extension Program, Pilot Program. (1991 December).
    UCLA Faculty in Mechanical, Aerospace, and Nuclear Engineering Dept. (School of Engineering and Applied Science)
  - Mellinkoff, David.
  - Memel, Sherwin L.
  - Meng, Mary Chow., - d.2010
  - Meyerhoff, Hans., b.1914 - d.1965
    UCLA Philosophy Department.
  - Menkes, John H., - d.2008 nov 22
  - Metev, Ivan.
  - Meyer, Robert J., b. 1952.
  - Meyers, Frederic., b. 1917 - d. 1999.
  - Mickey, Jean.
  - Migala, Pauline Gaynor (LASNS 1913, UCLA 1927)., b.1892 December 20 -
  - Miller, David H. (UCLA 1939, M.A. 1944, Ph.D. 1953)., d.2006 October 20
  - Miller, George Leslie., - d.2010
  - Miller, Kevin M.
  - Mills, Anthony F., b.1938 January 21
  - Millspaugh, Jesse F.
  - Millspaugh, Mary C.
  - Mingori, D. Lewis.
  - Mink, James Valentine., b.1923-
    Hired at UCLA as Assistant University Archivist, 1952 June; served as "Acting" University Archivist, c.1954-1964; became University Archivist, 1964-1972; promoted to Head of Special Collections & University Archivist, 1972; retired July 1, 1983.
  - Minkova, Donka.
  - Mischel, Paul.
  - Mitchell, Ann M.
  - Mitchell, Daniel J. B.
  - Mitchell-Kernan, Claudia.
    UCLA Vice Chancellor Graduate Studies (c.1995- )
  - Mitoma, Judy.
    UCLA Faculty, World Arts and Cultures; Director - Center for Intercultural Performance (World Arts and Cultures).
  - Mitsuyasu, Ronald.
  - Mittelbach, Frank G., b. 1924.
  - Mizrachi, Diane.
  - Mnookin, Jennifer.
  - Moldwin, Mark.
  - Molina, Kathy C.
  - Moore, Jean Macalister., b.1907 - d.2001 August 21
    Jean M. Moore served as the first art librarian, UCLA Library; wife of Everett T. Moore, former head of the UCLA Library Reference Department.
  - Moore, John Robert.
  - Moore, Steven.
  - Moore, Thomas C.
  - Morales, Armando Torres., b.1932 - d.2008
  - Morgan, J.D. (UCLA 1941), b.1919 - d.1980 December 16
    J.D. Morgan served as Head Tennis Coach (1950-1963) and as Director of Athletics (1963 July-1980 June).
  - Morris, Harry, n.d.
  - Morrison, James Douglas "Jim" (UCLA 1965 August)., b.1943 - d.1971
    Attended UCLA from 1964 September to 1965 August; member of The Doors (rock band; The Doors were previously called Rick and the Ravens).
  - Mortensen, Richard Edgar.
  - Moseley, Walter Strong (UCLA 1971).
  - Moss, Thelma Schnee (UCLA Ph.D. 1966)
  - Muller, Brian Reid.
  - Mulroy, Kevin.
    Appointed Associate University Librarian for Academic Services, 2008 November.
  - Muntz, Richard R.
  - Murakami, Momoko.
  - Murphy, Franklin David., b.1916 jan 29 - d.1994 jun 16
    UCLA Chancellor (1960 September 23-1968).
  - Murphy, George G. S.
    UCLA Faculty, Economics.
  - Murphy, Judith Harris (Mrs. Franklin D. Murphy)., b.1917- d.1998
  - Murphy, Marianne.
  - Nabokov, Peter.
  - Nathanson, Gloria.
  - Nattiv, Aurelia.
  - Neelin, J. David.
  - Nefkens, Bernard M.
  - Nel, Andre.
  - Nelson, Ernest.
  - Neutra, Richard Josef., b.1892 - d.1970
    Includes information on the UCLA Richard Neutra Memorial Lecture.
    Neutra was a Los Angeles-based architect.
  - Newcomer, Victor D., b.1916 April 5 - d.2002 March 15
    Professor of Medicine/Dermatology, 1961-1973.
  - Newsom, Jeanne Williams.
  - Nichols, Mary D.
  - Nickelsburg, Gerald (Jerry).
  - Nicols, Alfred., b. 1917 - d. 2011.
  - Nixon, Charles Robert., b.1917 August 9
    UCLA Professor Political Science, 1947-[c.1998].
  - Nobe, Ken., b.1925 August 26
    UCLA Faculty, Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering Department.
  - Noble, Howard S., b. 1893 - d. 1964.
  - Nofziger, Edward C. (UCLA 1936)
    Includes clippings of Nofziger's UCLA-related cartoons and cartoons published by King Features Syndicate, Inc.
  - Norman, Jerry.
  - Norton, Frank E., b. 1918 - d. 2005.
  - Nuiver, Marc.
  - Nunis, Doyce B., Jr.
  - Nussbaum, Felicity.
  - Oakes, Daniel.
  - Oakes, Jeannie., 2000s
  - Oakley, Charles W. (Duke)., 2000s
  - Oberg, Ruth Vivian (UCLA 1935). Diary., 1931-1933; 1934; 1932; 2 folders
  - Obichere, Boniface I., 1933-1997
  - O'Blath, Robert. Photographs., n.d.
  - O'Brian, Phillip. Photograph., n.d.
  - O'Brien, Patricia (Pat)., n.d.
  - O'Brien, Philip F., Photograph., n.d.
  - Obst, Frances M., 1909-1988
  - O'Byrne, Kathy., n.d.
  - Ochoa, Ralph M., 1998 February
  - Ochs, Elinor., 1998
  - O'Conner, Garrett., n.d.
  - O'Connor, Carroll., 1964
  - Odim, Jonah., 1998
  - O'Donnell, Cyril J., b. 1900 - d. 1976.
  - Oertel, Gerhard F.H., n.d.
  - Ogawa, Rikke., n.d.
  - Ogden, Elma. Photograph., n.s.
    UCLA football, 1993-1995 seasons.
  - Ohanian, Lee.
  - Ohen, Don. Photographs., 1953
  - Okada, John., 1967-1968
  - Okrent, David., 1990
  - Olian, Judy D.
  - Olsen, Steven.
  - Oppenheimer, Valerie Kincade., b.1932 October 25 - d.2009 November 2
    UCLA Faculty Sociology, 1968-1994.
  - Orchard, Henry John., b.1922 - d.2004
  - Orfield, Gary.
  - Osaga, William M.
  - Osborne, Alfred E. Jr., b. 1944.
  - Ornstein, Stanley I., b. 1939.
  - Ostrovsky, Rafail
  - Ostrum, Elinor (UCLA 1954, M.A. 1962, PhD. 1965).
    Ostrum received the 2009 Nobel Prize for Economics.
  - Ouchi, William G., b. 1943.
  - Ovbiagble, Bruce.
  - Paasonen, Aino.
  - Pacht, Jerry.
  - Packer, Sonya H.
  - Pagdin, Anthony.
  - Pagen, William.
  - Panunzio, Constantine M., b.1884 October 5 - d.1964 August 6
    UCLA Professor, Sociology; first faculty to teach sociology (also known as social science) at UCLA (1931).
  - Papalexis, Nancy.
  - Park, Kyeyoung.
  - Parker, Keith.
  - Parker, Neil.
  - Parker, Robert George.
  - Parker, Susan.
    Deputy University Librarian & Chief Financial Officer (appointed 2005 March).
  - Pateman, Carole.
  - Patton, Barbara., d.2004
  - Penman, Doris T.
  - Perrine, Richard Leroy., b.1924 May 15
    UCLA Faculty, Environmental Science and Engineering Program.
  - Peter, Michael Edward.
  - Peters, Elaine.
  - Pettitt, Roger Carlyle.
  - Philip, Duke of Edinburgh., b.1921-
    Speaker at Univeristy of California Charter Day (1966 March 14).
  - Pickett, Velma B. (UCLA 1935).
    Member of 'Daily Bruin" staff as an undergraduate; linguist, Ph.D. 1959 University of Michigan.
  - Pierskalla, William., b. 1934.
  - Pimentel, Rosa.
  - Pomraning, Gerald C., b.1936 February 23 - d.1999 February 6
    UCLA Faculty, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering.
  - Ponce, Walter.
  - Popek, Gerald.
  - Posnansky, Merrick.
  - Post, Jonathan.
  - Postley, John.
  - Postley, Judy Colyer (UCLA 1945)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark., b.1906 September 3 - d.2001 March 14
    UCLA Librarian (1944-1961); Director, William Andrews Clark Memorial Library (1944-1966) founder and Dean, UCLA School of Library Service (1959-1966).
  - Png, Ivan P. L., b. 1957.
  - Prasow, Paul., b. 1915 - d. 1982.
  - Preloran, Jorge., b.1933
    UCLA Theater, Film, & Television faculty (UCLA Ethnographic Film Program).
  - Propst, William S.
  - Prothro, J. Thompson "Tommy.", b.1920 July 20 - d.1995 May 14
    UCLA football backfield coach, 1949-1955; UCLA football coach, 1965-1971.
  - Putnam, A. Evelyn., b.1908 February 8 - d.1998
    Wife of William C. Putnam, UCLA Faculty-Geology.
  - Putterman, Seth.
  - Rada, Edward Louis., 1916-2005
  - Raia, Anthony P., b. 1928 - d. 2012.
  - Ramsey, James Blaine., b.1892 April 20 - d.1965 October 16
    UCLA Professor of Chemistry, Emeritus, 1923-1965.
  - Rankin, Jeffrey.
  - Rapp, Claudia.
  - Ratcliff, Ryan.
  - Raustiala, Kai.
  - Ray, Don.
  - Razavi, Behzah.
  - Reid, Henry G.
  - Retter, Yolanda.
  - Reuben, David B.
  - Reynolds, William Alonzo.
    UCLA student 1933 September to 1934 [January?]. Joined UCLA student Albert Wilkin Hamilton in declaring conscientious objector status regarding compulsory courses offered by the UCLA Military Science and Tactics Dept. (affiliated with the Reserve Officer Training Corps/ROTC); see: U.S. Supreme Court case Hamilton v. Regents of the University of California (1934).
  - Rice, Thomas H.
  - Rice, Thomas M.
  - Richard, Olga.
  - Richlin, Amy.
  - Richman, Barry., d. 1978.
  - Ridley, Florence.
  - Rieber, Charles Henry., b.1966 - d.1948
    UCLA Professor of Philosophy; namesake of Rieber Hall.
  - Rigler, Leo George., b.1896 - d.1979
  - Riley, Angela.
  - Rimer, David G.
  - Ringach, Dario.
  - Ringer, Lee.
  - Robbins, George W., b. 1905 - d. 1994.
  - Roberts, John Dombrowski.
  - Roberts, Polly.
  - Robinson, Jack Roosevelt (Jackie)., b.1919 - d.1972
    Attended UCLA 1939-1941.
  - Robinson, Lawrence Baylor., b.1919 September 14 - d.2005 March 21
    UCLA Faculty, Chemical Engineering.
  - Robinson, Rachel.
  - Robinson, William S.
  - Rodgers, Frank "Pepper."
    UCLA football Head Coach 1971-1973.
  - Rodriguez, Larissa V.
  - Rodriguez-Cepeda, Enrique.
  - Rogers, John.
  - Rogowski, Ronald.
  - Rose, Linda.
  - Rose, Mike.
  - Rosenbaum, Winifred Smith.
  - Rosenstein, Betty Rose Lebell (UCLA 1943).
    Includes Rosenstein's written recollections of a date, in 1941 while a student at UCLA.
  - Ross, Karl T.
  - Ross, Maria Rowena.
  - Rouse, Richard.
  - Roy, William.
  - Rubsamen, Walter H.
    UCLA Professor of Music.
  - Rumelt, Richard P.
  - Ruskin, Arnold.
  - Russell, Christopher T.
  - Ryan, Mary Josephine.
  - Ryan, Terry (Theresa).
    1986 - Head, ORION User Services (OUS).
  - Sachs, Carolyn.
  - Sandbrook, John.
  - Sandeen, Cathy A.
  - Sanders, Henry R. "Red."
    UCLA football coach, 1949-1957.
  - Sanlo, Ronni.
    Director, UCLA Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender (LGBT) Campus Resource Center.
  - Saposnik, Arieh.
  - Sarin, Rakesh K.
  - Sarnat, Bernard G., b.1912 September 1
    Professor of Oral Biology (UCLA School of Dentristry).
  - Sawhill, Clarence E., b.1906 November 5
    Clarence Sawhill, UCLA Band Director (1952-1972).
  - Sawyer, Charles H. "Tom", b. 1915 - d. 2006
  - Saxon, Andrew.
  - Saxon, David Stephen., b.1920 - d.2005
    UCLA Professor of Physics; University of California President, 1975-1983.
  - Schauwecker, Frederick., b.1896 August 31 - d.1975 February 1
    Frederick Schauwecker, piano accompianist, taught at UCLA Extension.
  - Scherrei, Rita A.
  - Schill, Michael H.
  - Schmidt, Warren., b. 1920.
  - Schnall, Peter.
  - Schoenberg, Arnold.
    UCLA Professor of Music (1936-1944); Faculty Research Lecturer (1941).
  - Schoenfield, Leslie Jack.
  - Schollhammer, Hans.
  - Schoppe, J. Palmer., b.1912 - d.2001
    UCLA Lecturer in Theater Arts.
  - Schwartz, Teri.
  - Schwartz, Thomas.
  - Scothorn, Carol.
    UCLA faculty, Dance.
  - Scott, Allen J.
  - Scott, David.
  - Searle Leach, Juda.
  - Seeds, Corrinne A., b.1889-d.1969
    Principal of the University Elementary School (UES), 1925-1957.
  - Seeger, Charles Louis, Jr., b.1886 December 14
    UCLA Regents' Professor in Department of Music, 1961 July-1962 January; Lecturer in Music, 1962 January-1963 June.
  - Segert, Stanislav.
  - Seidman, Dou.
  - Sellars, Peter.
  - Sellin, Paul Roland.
  - Serafetinides, Jean Rawlinson., b.1930 March 19 - d.2011 June 18
  - Setzer, Dawn.
  - Sharpe, Jenny.
  - Shaw, Stanford J.
    Includes: "Report of the Committee on Academic Freedom to the Academic Senate on Issues of Academic Freedom Arising Out of Threats To and Demonstrations Against Professor Stanford Shaw" (1983 February 8).
  - Shearer, Harry Julius (UCLA 196_), b.1943 December 23
    Reporter for "Daily Bruin" (1961).
  - Sheehan, Vivian (Joseph).
  - Sheldon, Sidney.
  - Shelton, Cynthia.
    Associate University Librarian for Collections and Technical Services (appointed September 1999).
  - Shelton, John P., b. 1920.
  - Shideler, Ross.
    UCLA Professor of Comparative Literature and Scandinavian Studies. Appointed Associate Dean to Graduate Division 2003 Dec. 1.
  - Shneidman, Edwin S. (UCLA 1938, M.A. 1940), b.1918 May 13 - d.2009 May
    UCLA Prof. of Medical Psychology (1970-1975, Neuropsychiatric Institute); UCLA Professor of Thanatology (1975-1988, Neuropsychiatric Institute). Founder of the Los Angeles Suicide Prevention Center (1958) and the American Association of Suicidology (1968).
  - Shorter, David Delgado.
  - Simmons, James Quimby.
  - Simpson, Mona.
  - Skerritt, Thomas A.
    Actor; attended UCLA as an undergraduate student 1960/1961 and 1961/1962 academic years.
  - Slater, James Arthur.
    Sir James Arthur Slater (M.P.) gave the 1938 Charter Day address at UCLA.
  - Slavenska, Mia Corak., b.1916 - d.2002 October 5
    Faculty member: Dance Department, [1969-1983?]; former ballerina with Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo.
  - Slichter, Louis Byrne., b.1896 - d.1978; Includes audio recording of March 1963 UCLA Faculty Lecture: "Gravity Observations and the Dynamics of the Earth."
    UCLA Emeritus Professor of Geophysics; Director, UCLA Institute of Geophysics; UC Thirty-eighth Annual Faculty Lecturer "Gravity Observations and the Dynamics of the Earth," 1963 March. SEE ALSO: Slichter Hall in Subject Files (Reference Collection)
  - Smith, Amy.
    UCLA Library Director of Development (appointed 2004 August).
  - Smith, Arthur L. see: Asanti, Molefi.
  - Smith, Dave.
  - Smith, Gjertrud Hjorth (UCLA 1930).
    Includes Gjertrud Hjorth Smith's (UCLA 1930) recollections of student life at the Vermont Ave. campus, the move to the Westwood campus, the UCLA Bond election, and the 1930 graduation ceremony at the Hollywood Bowl. (typed letter, 3 pgs., dated 1966 November 17)
  - Smith, Homer Austin., b.1931 October 9 - d.2011 April 10
    UCLA assistant football coach: offensive backfield coach (1973- ); offensive coordinator (1980- ).
  - Smith, Keith V., b. 1937 - d. 2011.
  - Smith, Laurence C.
  - Smith, Owen I., b.1946 January 18
  - Smith, Page. [Charles Page Smith], b.1917-d.1995
    UCLA History faculty (1952-1964); founding Provost of Coswell College, University of California, Santa Cruz (1964).
  - Smith, Wilbur J. (Jordan)
  - Snyder, Allegra Fuller.